# **Chris Roche**

Dallas, Texas

**©** chrismroche.com

☑ cmroche@gmail.com

**1** (910) 526-4674

#### **SUMMARY**

As a Senior Software Engineer with Raytheon Technologies, I have worked as a Scrum Master, Product Owner, and Software Architect. I excel at taking complex software products from requirements derivation to design, development, integration, and delivery. Extensive experience interacting with customers and other engineering and business disciplines. I am a fast learner with strong analytical and problem solving skills. I have a high work ethic and enjoy being challenged. A lifelong learner passionate about bringing new technologies from design to reality. Certified Scrum Master and former United States Marine with an active security clearance.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### **Raytheon Technologies**

McKinney, Texas

Senior Software Engineer

May 2017 - Present

- Software product technical lead, Scrum Master, Product Owner, Architect
- o Oversees software efforts through various product life-cycle phases and milestones
- Regularly assists other engineering disciplines with requirements development, system design, integration, and technical documentation
- Extensive experience in customer facing roles, technical communication, and presentation
- Lead system integrator on an emerging product. Experienced in ground and flight tests
- o Strong background in System Architecture, System Integration Test, Root Cause Corrective Action
- Software Cost Estimation and Basis of Estimate for programs and proposals
- Advanced technical education courses in Software Architecture, Principles of Systems Engineering, Machine Learning, and Electro-Optical Infrared systems
- Multiple Achievement Awards for technical leadership and program contributions
- Software Engineer of the Month in Business Unit for technical contributions

#### **United States Marine Corps**

Jacksonville, North Carolina

Intelligence Team Leader

February 2007 – February 2012

- Trained and led a ten-person team in a combat zone
- Intelligence Chief in a combat zone
- Routinely coordinated with and advised military and government agency leaders throughout the world
- Awarded Navy and Marine Corps Achievement Medal for excellence

#### RELEVANT SKILLS

**Environments** 

Windows, Linux, Real-Time Embedded Systems

**Programming Languages** 

C, C++, Python, R, Bash, Cuda, OpenCL

Tools
Machine Learning

Git, Jenkins, CMake, Eclipse, Visual Studio, CI Pipelines

EDA, NLP, Time Series, TensorFlow, Deep Learning,

Machine Learning for Embedded Systems

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Southern Methodist University**

M.Sc in Data Science, Concentration in Machine Learning

GPA: 4.00, Cum Laude

Dallas, Texas

August 2022

#### **University of North Texas**

B.Sc in Computer Engineering, Minor in Mathematics

GPA: 3.76, Cum Laude

Denton, Texas

May 2017

# **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

#### Master's Thesis and Capstone Project

*January 2022 – August 2022* 

 Automated Essay Evaluation and Student Feedback System using Natural Language Processing and Multi-Armed Bandit Recommender Engine

# **PUBLICATIONS**

 Chris Roche, Nathan Deinlein, Darryl Dawkins: Using Natural Language Processing to Increase Modularity and Interpretability of Automated Essay Evaluation and Student Feedback published in the SMU Data Science Review, Volume 6, 2022

# **VOLUNTEER ACTIVITIES**

- o Asst. Coach, McKinney Little League (October 2022 Present)
- Judge, Invention Convention U.S. Nationals (Multiple Years)
- o Judge, NASA Name the 2020 Rover (January 2020 March 2020)

# **INTERESTS**

Emerging Technologies, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Baseball